# **ROBERT HILL**

# **Summary**

Critical thinker with a passion for mining valuable data insights out of statistical analysis, compelling visualizations, and machine learning results. Former Big-Four consultant with experience in business process analysis and SDLC implementations of financial planning and reporting solutions.

# **Employment**

# Metis Data Science Bootcamp

Data Scientist

New York, NY Sep 2017 to Current

Metis is an immersive data science bootcamp with a focus on Python programming, machine learning, and statistical analysis. The full-time program is centered around building end-to-end projects (from acquisition, cleaning, and preprocessing to statistical modeling, visualization, and presentation) using real-world data. See "Projects" section for examples.

KPMG, LLP New York, NY

Management Consulting Associate

Jun 2013 to Aug 2013, Aug 2014 to Jul 2017

- Implemented a Hyperion Financial Management cash flow reporting solution as the technical reporting lead for requirements-gathering, design, testing, build, and user training for a multinational automotive manufacturer.
- Delivered strategic technology retirement initiatives and a development roadmap to achieve cost/efficiency benefits for the Controller, FP&A, and Treasury functions of a large financial services client.
- Owned status reporting, work plan management, and meeting minutes to support transition of numerous legacy financial planning, reporting and data consolidation systems to a Oracle EPM suite for a multinational agribusiness client.
- Developed training documentation and performed QA testing to support an Agile build of KPMG's Atlassian-based portal for purposes of promoting knowledge sharing and standardizing project delivery methods among advisory professionals.

## Quodd Financial Information Services, Inc.

Jersey City, NJ

IT Support Technician

Jun 2012 to Aug 2012

- Provided live technical support for an equity quote system to a network of over 700 clients (brokers, traders, independent investors).
- Triaged and investigated software defects while the company was integrating new data feed source systems.
- Led training and information sessions to teach customers about basic and advanced features of the Quodd platform.

# **Projects**

## **Exploring Craigslist Musicians Communities**

Created an interactive web app to explore Craigslist Musicians communities and the prevalence of algorithmically-generated topics in certain geographic areas. Scraped posts from the most active Craigslist Musicians sites in the U.S. and clustered posts via non-negative matrix factorization topic modeling.

# **The Starting Lineup**

Trained gradient-boosted tree regressors to predict weekly fantasy football performances for players in the 2017 NFL season. Achieved a season-average, root mean squared error of 5.6 points, beating ESPN's predictions by 0.5 points.

#### **Making Music Recommendations**

Trained a binary tree classifier to predict whether a user will re-listen to a given song using transactional, user, and song-specific data provided by a Taiwanese streaming music service.

## **Activities**

New York Cares Volunteer

Songwriter and Bass Player

# Contact

rjh336@stern.nyu.edu

rjh336.github.io

**\$** 954-684-2558

Queens, New York 11385

in robert-hill-24a32033

7 rjh336

# **Education**

NYU Stern School of Business BBA Finance / Information Systems 2014

# Skills

#### **PROGRAMMING**

Python

SQL

Javascript

HTML

CSS

Bash

Git

# LIBRARIES AND FRAMEWORKS

pandas

numpy

scikit-learn

xgboost

matplotlib

seaborn flask

d3.js

scrapy

selenium

lxml

sqlite3

#### DATA MANAGEMENT

PostgreSQL

AWS EC2

Fyce

Hyperion (Workspace, Reporting Studio, SmartView)